Finding Aid for the John Clough Papers, circa 1959-2002
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
- Articles and papers by other authors, 1960-2000, IV.; Folders 72-368
  - Soderberg, Stephen, 2001 (Box 14, Folder 340)
    Correspondence, 5 items
  - Soderberg, Stephen, 1997 (Box 14, Folder 341)
    White note fantasy. With review, correspondence, and notes
  - Steinbach, Peter, undated (Box 14, Folder 342)
    A case for the heptagon.
  - Steinbach, Peter, 1997 (Box 14, Folder 343)
    Golden fields: a case for the heptagon, In Mathematics Magazine 70:1, February 1997
  - Steinbach, Peter, undated (Box 14, Folder 344)
    Sections beyond golden.
  - Stephens, Peter W. and Goldman, Alan I., 1991 (Box 14, Folder 345)
    The structure of quasicrystals, In Scientific American April 1991
  - Stoecker, Philip, 2000 (Box 14, Folder 346)
    Axial isography as an extension of Klumpenhouwer networks. Examples for paper presented at Music Theory Society of New York State, April 8-9, 2000
  - Straus, Joseph N., 2001 (Box 14, Folder 347)
    A new model for voice leading in atonal music. Examples for paper presented at Society for Music Theory Meeting, Nov. 10, 2001
  - Straus, Joseph N., 1993 (Box 14, Folder 348)
    Voice leading in atonal music. Paper presented at Florida State University Music Theory Forum, 27 February 1993
  - Swinden, Kevin, 1994 (Box 14, Folder 349)
    Aspects of current theoretical thought on interval cycles. for class, MUS613, Theory of Scales, 14 December 1994. Originally in folder with residual notes for Scales, sets, and interval cycles: a taxonomy.
  - Swinden, Kevin, December 1994 (Box 14, Folder 350)
    Scriabin's late period: independent study report. Originally in folder with residual notes for Scales, sets, and interval cycles: a taxonomy.
  - Tam, Christine, 2002 (Box 14, Folder 351)
    The musical theory and microtonal compositions of Alois Haba (1893-1973). Thesis proposal, July 2, 2002
  - Thomas, Scott, 1993 (Box 14, Folder 352)
  - Thomas, Scott, undated (Box 14, Folder 353)
    Millileau rows.
  - Thomas, Scott, undated (Box 14, Folder 354)
    Vector products, evenness, and altered sets.
  - Vieru, Anatol, 1996-1997 (Box 14, Folder 355)
    Correspondence, 17 items
  - Vieru, Anatol, 1997 (Box 14, Folder 356)
    The "Other" music. With correspondence
  - Vinogradov, I. M., 1954 (Box 14, Folder 357)
    Elements of number theory. Photocopy. Translated from the fifth rev. ed. by Saul Kravetz. 1954
  - Watkins, Glenn, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 358)
  - Watkins, Glenn, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 359)
    Stravinsky and a theory of games. Examples for paper presented at University at Buffalo, 16 October 1995
  - Westergaard, Peter, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 360)
    Constructing a pitch system for tonal music. From An introduction to tonal theory, 1975
  - Wilson, Ervin M., 1964-1975 (Box 14, Folder 361)
    Correspondence with John H. Chalmers
  - Wilson, Ervin M., 1994 (Box 14, Folder 362)
    AILM 29, et al.
  - Wilson, Ervin M., 1994-1995 (Box 14, Folder 363)
    Scale-tree, 1994. With correspondence, 1995
  - Wilson, Ervin M., 1983 (Box 14, Folder 364)
    Some basic patterns underlying genus 12 & 17.
  - Unidentified, undated (Box 14, Folder 365)
    Appendix: Functions on groups.
  - Peck, Robert, 2002 (Box 14, Folder 366)
    Composite interval cycle sets, their relations, and applications. With review by Clough
  - Unidentified, undated (Box 14, Folder 367)
    A measure of eveness and maximally even sets.
  - Unidentified, 1993 (Box 14, Folder 368)
    The mystic chord and its chromatic modifications, (Scriabin).
- Subject and conference files, 1992-2000, V.; Folders 369-378
  Arranged alphabetically by subject. Folders also include notes and correspondence.
  - Berry, Wallace, 1992-1993 (Box 15, Folder 369)
    Correspondence regarding proposed publication of Berry's unpublished works
  - Buffalo Music Theory Working Group Meeting held at University at Buffalo, 28-29 July 1993 (Box 15, Folder 370)
    Correspondence, bibliography, proposal notes, etc.
  - Buffalo Music Theory Working Group Meeting held at University at Buffalo, July 28-29, 1993 (Box 15, Folder 371)
    John Clough's notes
  - Buffalo Music Theory Working Group Meeting held at University at Buffalo, July 18-19, 2001., The meeting was titled "2nd Buffalo Music Theory Symposium: Neo-Riemannian Transformations: mathematics and applications" (Box 15, Folder 372)
  - Evans, Bill (Box 15, Folder 373)
    Music for tunes composed or performed by pianist Bill Evans
  - International Symposium on Music and Mathematics (1994: Bucharest, Rumania) (Box 15, Folder 374)
    Program and correspondence
  - Neo-Riemannian theory issue of Journal of Music Theory 42:2, 1997-1998 (Box 15, Folder 375)
  - Neo-Riemannian Theory Symposium, University at Buffalo, July 2001, 2000-2001 (Box 15, Folder 376)
  - Society for Music Theory Meeting, Chapel Hill, North Carolina, December 1998 (Box 15, Folder 377)
    Papers on Riemann:
    Brown, Stephen C. Dual interval space in twentieth-century music
    Childs, Adrian P. Symmetric family values: notions of closeness in transformational systems
    Engebretsen, Nora. Psychological-aesthetic foundations and group-theoretic perspectives: triadic relations in Hostinský's Die Lehre von den musikalischen Klängen
    Gauldin, Robert. Further manifestation of the Douth2 relation in Tristan and Wagner's other music dramas
    Kopp, David. Subverting the dominant paradigm? shifting concepts of V in influential 19th century theories and some implications for today
    Mooney, Kevin. Musical syntax, the Tonnetz, Schubert's Impromptu
    Murphy, Scott. Generalized cyclical motions in Wagnerian triadic progressions
    Rehding, Alexander. Major thirds and German nationhood: Hugo Riemann's Myth of Ethnic Election
  - Three-gap theory, miscellaneous (Box 15, Folder 378)
    Fried, E., Sós, Vera T. A generalization of the three-distance theorem for groups, In Algebra Universalis 29, 1992
    Halton, John H. The distribution of the sequence In Proceedings of the Cambridge Philosophical Society 61, 1965
    Ruzsa, Imre Z. Generalized arithmetical progressions and sumsets Preprint no.: 38/1992, Mathematical Institute of the Hungarian Academy of Sciences
    Slater, Noel B. Gaps and steps for the sequence n0 mod 1 In Proceedings of the Cambridge Philosophical Society 63, 1967
    Sós, Vera T. On the distribution Mod 1 of the sequence na In Annales Universitatis Scientiarum Budapestinensis, 1958
- Grant applications, 1987-1991, VI.; Folders 379-382
  Arranged alphabetically by name of grant-funding institution.
  - American Society of Learned Societies, 1987 (Box 16, Folder 379)
  - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation Fellowship, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 380)
  - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation Fellowship, 1988 (Box 16, Folder 381)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities application for Fellowships for University Teachers, 1987?, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 382)
- Publications, undated, VII.; Folders 383-386
  Chiefly correspondence from publisher W. W. Norton regarding Clough's two books.
  - Basic Harmonic Progressions (Box 16, Folder 383)
    Comment cards from W.W. Norton
  - Scales, Intervals, Keys, Triads, Rhythm, and Meter (Box 16, Folder 384)
    Reviews, etc.
  - W.W. Norton (Box 16, Folder 385)
    Statements of royalties
  - W.W. Norton (Box 16, Folder 386)
- Bibliographies, 1969-1991, VIII.; Folders 387-402
  Arranged alphabetically by author of bibliography, interfiled with journal titles separately indexed.
  - Benjamin, William E. (Box 17, Folder 387)
    Publications record
  - Browne, Richmond (Box 17, Folder 388)
    Mind/Brain "stuff"
  - Christensen, Thomas (Box 17, Folder 389)
    Bibliography on tonal rhythm
  - Clough, John (Box 17, Folder 390)
    A bibliography of writings in English on atonal and serial music and set-theoretic analysis (1979-1985)
  - The computer and the humanities (Box 17, Folder 391)
    Indexes for 1969-1975
  - Dissertation Abstracts International. (Box 17, Folder 392)
    Music and the performing arts, selected collection of doctoral dissertations and masters theses, 1987-1991
  - In Theory Only (Box 17, Folder 393)
    Indexes for 1955-1970
  - Indiana Theory Review (Box 17, Folder 394)
    Indexes for v.1-3
  - Intégral (Box 17, Folder 395)
    Indexes to 1987-2000
  - Journal of Music Theory (Box 17, Folder 396)
    Indexes for v. 1-17
  - Lewin, David (Box 17, Folder 397)
    Bibliography of his works
  - Nolan, Catherine (Box 17, Folder 398)
    Bibliography from master's thesis, Symmetric inversion: a sign of tonality, 1983
  - Perspectives of New Music (Box 17, Folder 399)
    Indexes to v. 1-15
  - Smith, Charles J. (Box 17, Folder 400)
    An annotated bibliography of the work of Heinrich Schenker
  - Smith, Charles J. Gioseffo Zarlino: a beginner's guide and bibliography (Box 17, Folder 401)
  - Van den Toorn, Pieter C. (Box 17, Folder 402)
    Stravinsky
- Annotated books, 1973-1990, IX.; Folders 403-407
  Arranged alphabetically by author and then in order by receipt.
  - Forte, Allan The Structure of Atonal Music, 1973 (Box 17, Folder 403)
  - Forte, Allan The Structure of Atonal Music, 1977 printing (paperback) (Box 17, Folder 404)
  - Stark, Harold M. An Introduction to Number Theory, 1981 printing (paperback) (Box 17, Folder 405)
Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog.
Subjects
Music theorists--New York (State)--Buffalo; Music theory--20th century; Music theory--Bibliography
Genres
Correspondence